inspiremore.com 2019-06-02

# Privacy

InspireMore Privacy Policy. Last Updated July 5, 2018.

**InspireMore** values the privacy of those who use our website (“Site”), products and services and makes all commercially reasonable efforts to protect it. This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices of InspireMore (“InspireMore,” “we,” “our” or “us”), which owns and operates a website, [InspireMore.com](http://inspiremore.com/ "InspireMore"). Your access to and use of the services on InspireMore website (collectively, “InspireMore Services”) are subject to InspireMore Terms of Service and all applicable laws.

This privacy policy describes how and when InspireMore collects, uses, and shares information when you use InspireMore Services. InspireMore may receive your information through your mobile device, website, email notifications, or other interactions with InspireMore Services. When using any InspireMore Services you consent to the collection, transfer, manipulation, storage, disclosure or other uses of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. Regardless of which country you reside in or supply information from, you authorize InspireMore to use your information in the United States and any other country where InspireMore operates.

We value your comments about our privacy statement and invite you to e-mail us with inquiries, suggestions and complaints at:[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#1e767b7272715e77706d6e776c7b73716c7b307d7173214d6b7c747b7d6a234f6b7b6d6a7771703b2c2e4c7b797f6c7a7770793b2c2e4e6c77687f7d673b2c2e4e7172777d67). Please read the following to learn more about what information we collect, what we do with that information, and how we may use your personal information.

**Information Collected.**

How Information is Collected. To enhance your user experience and improve the InspireMore Services, InspireMore collects information about you from two sources: (i) information you affirmatively give to us; and (ii) information automatically collected when you use any InspireMore Services (“InspireMore”). Third parties may also collect your information in connection with your use of InspireMore Services unless a user refuses to consent to the disclosure of information to third parties.

Information You Affirmatively Give Us. In using InspireMore Services, you may provide us with personally identifiable information. This refers to information about you that can be used to contact or identify you, and information on your use of and activities at our website that may be connected with you (“Personal Information”). Personal Information that we collect may include, but is not limited to, your name, username, email address, and password. Personal Information may also include information you supply to us concerning your preferences, geographic location, and interests expressed in the course of use InspireMore Services.

Information Automatically Collected. We also collect information about your visit from the browser on your computer (via Cookies and other tracking technologies as defined below) or mobile device including but not limited to the time and date you visit the InspireMore Services, your geographic location, IP address, device information, cookies and the pages you request — to analyze trends, administer the site, track your navigation of the site, deliver relevant advertisements and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use (note that IP addresses are not linked to “personally identifiable information”). Additionally, we collect aggregate information from multiple users without personally identifying individuals, such as geographic region, which we may share with our business partners (who include third party service providers, advertisers, advertising networks and platforms, agencies, and distribution partners) — to improve understanding of customer needs and provide relevant services.

By using InspireMore Services, you are giving InspireMore permission to use and store such information consistent with this privacy policy.

Creating an InspireMore Account and Profile Information. There are two (2) types of InspireMore accounts that can be created, one account can be created for select authors chosen by InspireMore and the other account can be created by users from the general public. When you create a InspireMore account, you provide access credentials in the form of a username, email address, and password or by authentication using another service, such as Facebook. You may optionally provide us with additional profile information, including a short bio, location, and profile picture. If you create your InspireMore account by connecting through another service, we may use public information from the connected account to help complete your InspireMore profile. You may update or modify your profile information and contact information at any time. Profile information is available publicly on InspireMore Services, such as on your profile page.

Content, Following, and Other Public Information. InspireMore is a website geared toward inspiring others on a daily basis, so some information you provide us is information that you choose to be made public. This includes not only the content that you post and data provided with such content, such as when it was posted, but also the content you follow, the content that you like or comment on, and other public interactions on InspireMore Services. Your public information is broadly and instantly disseminated. For instance, your profile information and public content are immediately delivered to a wide range of users and other services that access InspireMore. When you share information or content via InspireMore Services, you should think carefully about what you are making public.

Location Information. In addition to profile information, you may also tell us your exact location if you choose to enable your mobile device to send us location information. We may use and store information about your location to provide features of our Services.

**How We Use Personal Information**

Use of Personal Information. Personal Information is or may be used for the following purposes: (i) to provide and improve InspireMore Services, (ii) to administer your use of InspireMore Services, (iii) to enable you to enjoy and easily navigate the InspireMore Services, (iv) to better understand your needs and interests, (v) to fulfill requests you may make, (vi) to personalize your experience, (vii) to provide or offer software updates and product announcements, and (viii) to provide you with further information and offers from us or third parties that we believe you may find useful or interesting, including newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information on services and products offered by us or third parties.

We use information we obtain by technical means (such as the automatic recording performed by our servers or through cookies) for the above purposes and to monitor and analyze use of InspireMore Services; for technical administration of InspireMore Services; to increase functionality and user-friendliness of InspireMore Services; to better tailor InspireMore Services to your needs, and to generate and derive useful data and information concerning the interests, characteristics, and user behavior of our users.

Sharing of Information. When you send information to InspireMore Services, you are granting InspireMore permission to use and take other actions regarding such information (as described in the Terms of Service) to provide InspireMore Services. We do not share, sell, rent or otherwise distribute this information to others, except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy. InspireMore may share your information with others outside of InspireMore under the following circumstances:

We have your explicit consent to share the information;

We need to share your information to fulfill your service request;

We wish to contact you with information about services from our business partners;

We have a good faith belief that sharing or otherwise permitting access, disclosure, use or preservation of such information is reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations;

We believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud or potential threats against persons or property;

We believe it is necessary to investigate potential violations of our Terms of Service, or to enforce those Terms of Service; or

We have a relationship with an affiliate or partner you have an online or off-line (non-Internet) relationship with, or have visited the affiliate or partner’s website that links to or mentions InspireMore Services, and have registered for InspireMore Services through the partner or affiliate’s program or website.

**With Whom Information Is Shared**

Public Information – InspireMore may share as it sees fit information that you voluntarily make public. Since such public information can be accessed by the public and used by any member of the public, such use by third parties is beyond the control of InspireMore.

When you post content on the InspireMore Services, we also collect, process, and store the contents of the InspireMore Services on our servers. The contents of the InspireMore Services can also be temporarily stored on the devices of users. We cannot prevent others from making copies of your content (e.g. taking a screenshot). You should not use InspireMore to send messages if you want to be certain that the general public cannot keep a copy.

Personal Information – If we have your express consent, InspireMore may share your personal information it collects with business partners and other third parties that are not affiliated with InspireMore. InspireMore will never share your personal information without your consent, unless compelled to do so by law.

Under narrow circumstances, InspireMore may disclose your personal information without asking for your consent to protect the legal rights of InspireMore or its affiliates, and each of their respective investors, directors, officers, employees, agents, and suppliers; to protect the safety and security of users of the InspireMore Services or to enforce our Terms of Services; to protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or to comply with or respond to the law or legal process or a request for cooperation by a government entity, whether or not legally required. If you notify us you believe your legal rights have been violated by InspireMore or another user of InspireMore Services, we may provide the information you provide to us to others if we believe it is necessary to evaluate and respond to your complaint. For instance, if you submit a notice of copyright infringement to us, we may send a copy to the person or entity who uploaded, stored, or transmitted the material addressed by the communication.

**Non-Personal Information and Aggregate Data**

InspireMore may share with third parties your non-personal information and related aggregated data. For example, InspireMore may share IP addresses or general demographic information of its users to provide anonymous aggregated data to business partners (i.e. third party service providers, advertisers, advertising networks and platforms, agencies, and distribution partners) about the volume of use on InspireMore Services and the specific InspireMore Services in which users are most interested. Because this form of data does not identify particular users, these third parties will not be able to contact you based solely on this data.

**Change of Control**

If InspireMore sells all or part of its business, makes a sale or transfer of assets, is otherwise involved in a merger or business transfer, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy, InspireMore may transfer your personal information and non-personal information to one or more third parties as part of such transaction.

**How You Can Control the Information We Collect, Use and Share**

You have the choice about whether to disclose your personal information or other information about yourself to InspireMore. Regardless of your choices regarding promotional communications and updates regarding content, InspireMore may send you administrative messages, service announcements, terms and conditions of your account, or other similar communications, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them.

You may stop using your account on the InspireMore Services at any time by simply logging out. You can also choose to remove your account by contacting us via the contact method below. Please note that if you choose to cancel your account, InspireMore may retain some information about you such as for analytical purposes, the content you submitted to the Services, as well as for record keeping integrity.

**Location**

When you first launch any features of the InspireMore Service that collect location information, you will be asked to consent to our collection of this information. You may stop our collection of location information by following the standard uninstall process to remove the InspireMore Services from your device.

**Cookies**

To enhance your online experience, we and our Partners use cookies and other tracking technologies. Cookies are text files stored in your computer’s browser to store your preferences. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your browser, pass on computer viruses, or capture your e-mail address. InspireMore Services use cookies for user authentication (e.g. remembering your login information to keep you logged in upon your next visit of the Site), keeping track of your preferences (such as content you’ve saved, authors and topics you follow, email newsletters to which you’ve opted-in, etc.), promotional campaigns that require user identification, keeping track of our audience size and traffic patterns, and to deliver relevant advertising from both first and third party advertising partners. You can configure your browser to accept cookies, reject cookies or notify you when a cookie is being used.

If you would like more information about web tags and cookies associated with online advertising or to opt-out of third-party collection of this information, please visit the [ Network Advertising Initiative](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) or [ Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). To the greatest extent permissible under applicable law, we are not responsible for the tracking practices of third parties in connection with the InspireMore website.

**Links**

The InspireMore website and services may contain links to other sites. InspireMore is not responsible for the privacy policy or other practices employed by websites linked to, or from, our website nor the information or content contained therein. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.

**International Users**

InspireMore abides by the safe harbor framework set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information collected from the European Union. The following link provides more information about the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Program: [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/](https://www.export.gov/safeharbor/ "http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/").

**Our Policy Toward Children**

The Services are not directed to children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian learns his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#573f323b3b38173e3924273e25323a3825327934383a680422353d3234236a06223224233e38397265670532303625333e393072656707253e2136342e72656707383b3e342e). If we learn a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

**Changes and Updates**

From time to time, we may change this privacy policy. To ensure that you are familiar with our most updated policies and practices, check the effective date indicated above of this privacy policy each time you use InspireMore Services. If we make any changes, we will notify you of such changes by posting the updated privacy policy on the InspireMore website. We may also send you an email alerting you of such changes. You will be bound by any such changes to the policy when you use InspireMore Services after those changes have been posted. If we make material revisions concern practices where we have represented we will obtain your consent to use or disclose your personal information, we will obtain your consent before taking any action inconsistent with those representations.

If InspireMore should ever sell its assets, merge with another entity or file for bankruptcy, information collected from this website and in the operation of the services may be transferred as assets of InspireMore.

**Contact Us**

InspireMore welcomes your feedback regarding this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service. If you have questions, comments, or concerns about either one, please contact us by e-mail at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a4ccc1c8c8cbe4cdcad7d4cdd6c1c9cbd6c18ac7cbc99bf7d1c6cec1c7d099f5d1c1d7d0cdcbca819694f6c1c3c5d6c0cdcac3819694f4d6cdd2c5c7dd819694f4cbc8cdc7dd).
